<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>linguistics on Michaela</title>
    <link>http://michaelacheong.com/tags/linguistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linguistics on Michaela</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 15:25:53 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://michaelacheong.com/tags/linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phonology</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/phonology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 15:25:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/phonology/</guid>
      <description>General Tips1 Learn the IPA ASAP Associate a keyword with IPAs that are harder Remember the internal logic of common IPA charts (looks like a head turned left) Use a blank IPA chart Common transcription errors in vowels and stress Finding stress: say word in sing-song like someone&amp;rsquo;s name, and syllable with highest pitch is primary stress IPA Chart Vowels Clickable IPA Charts
Interactive Sagittal Section
Consonants 1. Speech Organs 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OzCLO</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/ozclo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:49:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/ozclo/</guid>
      <description>OzCLO is the Australian Computational Linguistics Olympiad. I participated in it during high school. In Grade 10, my junior team beat out the third best senior team in our state, so they actually didn&amp;rsquo;t participate in the national round. In the regional round, we came first for juniors, and then in my senior year we came first in our state (i.e. in the regional round).
I thoroughly enjoyed all of my experiences to do with OzCLO during high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguistics</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/linguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/linguistics/</guid>
      <description>I think linguistics is really cool. There is an entire story behind how I got interested in linguistics, which I would like to write up at some point.
OzCLO QTE Wycliffe Talking to a ling prof from Griffith Naomi&amp;rsquo;s parents Graeme&amp;rsquo;s wife&amp;rsquo;s parents For now, this is going to be a sort of quick guide based on my linguistics intro subject at uni, but I will only be trying to revise the topics below so these may not be super comprehensive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
