<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>relationships on Momentos from Michaela</title>
    <link>https://michaelacheong.com/tags/relationships/</link>
    <description>Recent content in relationships on Momentos from Michaela</description>
    <image>
      <title>Momentos from Michaela</title>
      <url>https://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 11:03:24 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michaelacheong.com/tags/relationships/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dating</title>
      <link>https://michaelacheong.com/dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 11:03:24 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelacheong.com/dating/</guid>
      <description>Youth Talk by Snr Pastor 2021-10-22 When? Past 18 and when your parents say you can
What? Exclusive, between friendship and engagement. To be done WITH OTHERS, not alone
Purpose: not just a fun experience, but to find a life partner. Is this &amp;ldquo;the one&amp;rdquo;?
Dating is an incubator where love can develop.
But also there are DANGERS! Eg. When they ignore their other friends when they get together
Phase 1: Goosebumps Phase 2: Weaknesses and doubt Phase 3: Break-up You need your FRIENDS through this</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postpone intimacy in dating</title>
      <link>https://michaelacheong.com/postpone-intimacy-in-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 11:03:17 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelacheong.com/postpone-intimacy-in-dating/</guid>
      <description>You won&amp;rsquo;t regret going slower and guarding each other. But many people regret moving too fast?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pursue clarity in dating</title>
      <link>https://michaelacheong.com/pursue-clarity-in-dating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 11:03:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelacheong.com/pursue-clarity-in-dating/</guid>
      <description>Questions to ask:
What have you learned about each other lately — stories, habits, character traits? How have you each grown in your relationship with Jesus since you started dating? Are you both committed to abstaining from any form of sexual immorality? What flags, if any, have others raised about your relationship? What obstacles are keeping the two of you from getting married? Are you each being driven by your own desires, or by God’s desires for you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is better to marry than to burn with passion</title>
      <link>https://michaelacheong.com/better-to-marry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 09:25:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelacheong.com/better-to-marry/</guid>
      <description>This was just an interesting verse from my bible reading today.
To the unmarried and the widows I say that it is good for them to remain single, as I am. But if they cannot exercise self-control, they should marry. For it is better to marry than to burn with passion. (1 Corinthians 7:8–9)
Going through 1 Corinthians myself for the first time has been a very interesting journey. Onwards we go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
