<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mental-health on Museum of Michaela</title>
    <link>http://michaelacheong.com/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mental-health on Museum of Michaela</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://michaelacheong.com/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bipolar disorder</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/bipolar-disorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/bipolar-disorder/</guid>
      <description>What is it Mood disorder Chronic condition causing intense mood changes Who does it affect? 1 in 50 Aussies Onset: teens/young adults Women &amp;gt; men Characterised by Periods of extreme moods Manic (hypomanic) episodes Extreme euphoria, high Can be high-functioning Hypomania is &amp;rsquo;less than mania&#39; Depressive episodes Hopelessness, low energy Can last weeks or months Symptoms (direct quote1) During a manic phase, symptoms may include: feeling high, extremely happy or irritable inflated self-esteem or grandiose ideas increased energy, activity and creativity, along with a reduced need to sleep an increase in task-focused behaviours (such as staying up all night to get things done) racing thoughts and speech (may be expressed as frequently talking over people) jumping from topic to topic being very easily distracted by any stimuli (such as noises or other people) impulsive or risky behaviours with spending, business or sexual activity unrealistic plans, delusions or hallucinations During a depressive phase, symptoms may include: low mood lack of motivation a loss of interest in usual leisure activities or hobbies changes in sleep patterns difficulty concentrating withdrawing from social contact and activities feelings of worthlessness or guilt, which may include suicidal thoughts Types Bipolar I long-lasting periods of extreme mood (either mania or depression) can include psychosis Bipolar II less-extreme highs (hypomania) episodes last for a few hours/days Cyclothymic disorder less severe, still impacts daily function Substance-induced bipolar disorder Causes Here it will be made clear why I have an irrational fear about developing bipolar disorder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trauma-informed care</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/trauma-informed-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 20:33:01 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/trauma-informed-care/</guid>
      <description>Trauma-informed care is based on the understanding that:
a significant number of people living with mental health conditions have experienced trauma in their lives trauma may be a factor for people in distress the impact of trauma may be lifelong trauma can impact the person, their emotions and relationships with others.1
Churchy stuff 4 Focus-Areas for Creating a Trauma-Informed Ministry Trauma-Informed Youth Ministry Preaching Tool Intro - Safer Spaces Toolkit What is trauma-informed care?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You should not force yourself to do schoolwork when you feel bleh.</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/schoolwork-when-bleh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:25:17 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/schoolwork-when-bleh/</guid>
      <description>A short guide to handling your education when life is falling apart around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Olympics</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/trauma-olympics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:04:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/trauma-olympics/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: totally based on personal experience, and not properly researched. Think of it as pop psychology.
To participate in the Trauma Olympics is to partake in the competition of &amp;ldquo;who has experienced the worst trauma?&amp;rdquo;. What metrics are used? Quantity (how many events, for how long) and quality (how bad was it). This is not a great culture to participate in, but I have found myself falling victim to it from others and equally perpetuating it onto others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Existential dread</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/existential-dread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 12:07:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/existential-dread/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I get this horrible feeling in my stomach. It&amp;rsquo;s happens in a moment where I sort of realise that I am an actual human on the earth. It&amp;rsquo;s a strange sensation. I feel this pit in my stomach, and the world seems a bit too real for a couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
