<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michaela</title>
    <link>http://michaelacheong.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michaela</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:01:37 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://michaelacheong.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Michaela&#39;s Digital Garden</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 08:53:38 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Start here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complex Analysis</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/complex-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 16:01:37 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/complex-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I have an exam coming up, so going to try and make this page into a big fat guide to complex analysis.
Basic formulas (sin(z) = \frac{e^{z} + e^{-z}}{2i})
Another test Cauchy integral formula extension
$$ f(z)^{(n)} = stuff$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trauma Olympics</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/trauma-olympics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 10:04:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/trauma-olympics/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: totally based on personal experience, and not properly researched. Think of it as pop psychology.
To participate in the Trauma Olympics is to partake in the competition of &amp;ldquo;who has experienced the worst trauma?&amp;rdquo;. What metrics are used? Quantity (how many events, for how long) and quality (how bad was it). This is not a great culture to participate in, but I have found myself falling victim to it from others and equally perpetuating it onto others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking caution with my K-Pop</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/kpop-caution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 09:38:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/kpop-caution/</guid>
      <description>I got into K-Pop quite a while ago, but since becoming more serious about my faith have often walked back from idolatry to just music enjoyment. I have also recently been thinking I should pay more attention to the meaning of the songs I listen to, even if they&amp;rsquo;re in a different language. That is going to take&amp;hellip; a lot of work. But I think it will start with filtering out the new songs that come into my sphere of attention and going through the entire discography of Red Velvet and LOONA to sort out the ones I should keep around vs the ones I could chuck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crucifixion is a form of public shame and humiliation</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/crucifixion-connotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 09:33:07 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/crucifixion-connotations/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways people die, and many ways that death is made public within the confines of the law, depending on where you are in time and space. While Jesus was around, crucifixion, aside from being up there as one of the most painful forms of execution and death, was a public scene of shame and humiliation for whoever was hung upon a cross. There was a strong cultural and social element to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All things are lawful...</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/all-things-are-lawful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 09:32:44 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/all-things-are-lawful/</guid>
      <description>but...</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical fashion</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/ethical-fashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 15:17:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/ethical-fashion/</guid>
      <description>A topic as chunky as my Doc Marten soles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSCode</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 09:26:13 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/vscode/</guid>
      <description>I think you call this a stack, where you talk about applications you use and their setup. So, I am gonna write a university stack, or a general productivity stack, but this is my VSCode stack, which in essence is a list of extensions I use and my setup.
 Colour Theme: Rouge  I like navy and the soft pink is really nice. -I also have used Horizon Bright by jolaleye if I ever want to use a light theme (so, not super often, but enough to say I like it as a theme).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OzCLO</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/ozclo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:49:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/ozclo/</guid>
      <description>OzCLO is the Australian Computational Linguistics Olympiad. I participated in it during high school. In Grade 10, my junior team beat out the third best senior team in our state, so they actually didn&amp;rsquo;t participate in the national round. In the regional round, we came first for juniors, and then in my senior year we came first in our state (i.e. in the regional round).
I thoroughly enjoyed all of my experiences to do with OzCLO during high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linguistics</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/linguistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 10:49:08 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/linguistics/</guid>
      <description>I think linguistics is really cool. There is an entire story behind how I got interested in linguistics, which I would like to write up at some point.
 OzCLO QTE Wycliffe Talking to a ling prof from Griffith Naomi&amp;rsquo;s parents Graeme&amp;rsquo;s wife&amp;rsquo;s parents  For now, this is going to be a sort of quick guide based on my linguistics intro subject at uni, but I will only be trying to revise the topics below so these may not be super comprehensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunning-Kruger Effect</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/dunning-kruger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 08:40:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/dunning-kruger/</guid>
      <description>The Dunning-Kruger Effect is the psychological phenomenon wherein people display a cognitive bias towards their own abilities: those with limited competence or knowledge will overestimate their abilities and demonstrate great confidence in themselves, whilst those with increasing or expert-level competence are reserved in self-confidence as they acknowledge the limitations of their knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving out</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/moving-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 12:07:51 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/moving-out/</guid>
      <description>I am moving out soon. Here are some helpful resources:
 Queensland, Australia-based organisations  Residential Tenancies Authority | Students https://www.rta.qld.gov.au/before-renting/choosing-a-rental-property/students Queensland Youth Housing Coalition | First Time Renter: A step by step guide to getting a rental property https://www.qyhc.org.au/first-time-renter/ QLD Govt | Moving out of home https://www.qld.gov.au/youth/life-skills-turning-18/moving-out-of-home Legal Aid | Moving out https://www.legalaid.qld.gov.au/Find-legal-information/Relationships-and-children/Children-and-parenting/Moving-out   Australian resources  MoneySmart | Moving out of home https://moneysmart.gov.au/student-life-and-money/moving-out-of-home Zoom Removals | Epic House Moving Checklist https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Existential dread</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/existential-dread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 12:07:21 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/existential-dread/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, I get this horrible feeling in my stomach. It&amp;rsquo;s happens in a moment where I sort of realise that I am an actual human on the earth. It&amp;rsquo;s a strange sensation. I feel this pit in my stomach, and the world seems a bit too real for a couple of seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is better to marry than to burn with passion</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/better-to-marry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 09:25:28 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/better-to-marry/</guid>
      <description>This was just an interesting verse from my bible reading today.
 To the unmarried and the widows I say that it is good for them to remain single, as I am. But if they cannot exercise self-control, they should marry. For it is better to marry than to burn with passion. (1 Corinthians 7:8–9)
 Going through 1 Corinthians myself for the first time has been a very interesting journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hold all things loosely</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/hold-loosely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 09:23:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/hold-loosely/</guid>
      <description>On Sunday, we went through 1 John 2:12-17, however, 1 John 2:15–17 is a bit more relevant to this thought.
 Do not love the world or the things in the world. If anyone loves the world, the love of the Father is not in him. For all that is in the world—the desires of the flesh and the desires of the eyes and pride of life—is not from the Father but is from the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 21:54:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/css/</guid>
      <description>I only slightly want to claw my eyes out. May I please just have pretty fonts?
https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/CSS/Styling_text/Web_fonts https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/how-to-load-assets-from-the-static-folder-in-a-css-file/21005 Need to fix theme-vars.css with my actual desired fonts lol</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 18:28:20 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/now/</guid>
      <description>This is a bucket of all of the things currently simmering away in my brain.
 Moving out University exams loom Kids holiday program coming up! Best time of the year ngl I&amp;rsquo;ve been paying too much attention to Queendom 2 This website  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To write</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/to-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 16:44:01 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/to-write/</guid>
      <description>Lots and lots of collecting all of my God-related thoughts that are randomly scribbled on paper which, while nice, are not easy to look back on sometimes How I came to understand God&amp;rsquo;s grace The Gospel for beginners The Bible for beginners Quiet times?? Fonts, typography, favourite fonts Mathematics, subjects I&amp;rsquo;m taking, transfer statistics knowledge onto digital garden maybe?? High school, reflections, why it sucked (i.e. having mental health but as a high achiever) Music, instruments Crochet, yarn and hook stuff Anything from Notion that I sort of don&amp;rsquo;t want in Notion anymore (I am a bit sick of Notion) A rant about Notion Anki setup The difficultiy I have in sticking to systems Bullet journalling (Ryder Carroll basics) Stationery How I feel about receiving flowers as gifts K-Pop?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:34:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/github/</guid>
      <description>I am an absolute GitHub noob, but like, I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best.
When I created this website, I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise I should have created the hugo new site in a cloned repository that was already on my computer, so, I am using the second answer of this stack overflow question to do it. https://stackoverflow.com/questions/3311774/how-to-convert-existing-non-empty-directory-into-a-git-working-directory-and-pus
After some finicking, I now have my Hugo site version control being managed in Git. I think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is Michaela?</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/who-is-michaela/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:05:04 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/who-is-michaela/</guid>
      <description>Origins of the name Michaela Michaela
n. who is like God
Feminine form of Michael (from Hebrew).
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michaela
A girl from my Youth group wrote this out on a card for me in nice hand-lettering and gave it to me when I got baptised in March of 2021. I honestly hadn&amp;rsquo;t thought about the meaning of my name until then, though I knew that I had been named Michaela based on the biblical angel Michael.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:04:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/hugo/</guid>
      <description>What I use to make my site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital garden</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/digital-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:04:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/digital-garden/</guid>
      <description>A digital garden is a place for thoughts, knowledge and ideas to grow.
The main reference for what a digital garden is comes from Maggie Appleton. I will not follow the original ethos to the T, but it&amp;rsquo;s a very nice read nonetheless.
For me, the main pull towards maintaining a digital garden is that it&amp;rsquo;s not as intensive as a blog. As outlined in Maggie&amp;rsquo;s writing, a blog requires you to do all of this background research before eventually deciding to release a perfectly manicured opinion to the internet, exerting your intellectual authority onto all who pass through your site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, it began</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/so-it-began/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 15:04:25 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/so-it-began/</guid>
      <description>I was trying to figure out how to make this website and what exactly it would hold and communicate to the rest of the billions of people with an internet connection. Not that I expect an audience, but once things are out in the world, they stay there. A blog seemed limiting, and I got caught up in a lot of websites recommending I choose a niche and stick to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
