<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>faith on Michaela</title>
    <link>http://michaelacheong.com/tags/faith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in faith on Michaela</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 20:45:51 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://michaelacheong.com/tags/faith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Being a Christian university student</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/christian-university-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 20:45:51 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/christian-university-student/</guid>
      <description>I had a massive crisis in the middle of my first year of uni. As I grew in my faith and left high school (which was pretty bad for me), I became disillusioned with the idea of studying. What is the point of me spending this time in uni, studying for a degree that isn&amp;rsquo;t a theological degree? I could spend all day studying my Bible but instead I must study linear analysis?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:55:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/love/</guid>
      <description>I feel like a lot of stuff I have been reading or hearing has been about love. That makes sense, given love is the core of who God is. God IS love. Of course I am learning a lot about love.
The classic is 1 Corinthians 13. Anything without love is nothing.
Let all that you do be done in love, 1 Corinthians 16:14.
Little children, let us not love in word or talk but in deed and in truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suffering produces faith</title>
      <link>http://michaelacheong.com/suffering-produces-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 10:29:45 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michaelacheong.com/suffering-produces-faith/</guid>
      <description>17/06/2022
Today, I started reading 2 Corinthians, and like, wow. There are times when I am in awe at God&amp;rsquo;s word, but this was a time where I was TRULY felt so in awe of what I was reading.
In the first half of 2 Corinthians 1, Paul talks about the afflictions and suffering he&amp;rsquo;s gone through. There are a few key truths I have taken from this:
Suffering makes us learn to rely on God I have gone through a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
